iditarod.com 2019-04-22

# Iditarod.com Website Privacy Policy – Iditarod

The Iditarod Trail Committee, Inc. (“ITC”) is strongly committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information. The policies below are applicable to Iditarod.com website (“Website”) produced and maintained by ITC. We have established this security and privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) to let you know the kinds of personal information we may gather during your visit to the Website, why we gather your information, what we use your personal information for, when we might disclose your personal information, and how you can manage your personal information.

Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy apply only to information gathered through the Website and do not necessarily reflect our practices with respect to information gathered through other websites that we operate or through other off-line means.

By visiting the Website, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Website. We reserve the right to modify or amend the terms of our Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or do not see your concerns addressed here, you should contact us by email at shooley@iditarod.com.

**What Information About Me Is Collected and Stored?**  
ITC adheres to the highest standards of ethical practices in all of our operations and is dedicated to protecting the privacy of all visitors to our Website. Our privacy policy is simple: Except as disclosed below, we don’t sell, barter, give away, or rent your personal information to any company outside of ITC. One of the basic principles we’ve tried to follow in designing the Website is that we ask for only the information we need to provide the service you’ve requested. As a result, what information we collect and store depends almost entirely on how you choose to make use of the Website.

**Personal Information**  
We collect and store information that you enter into the Website. For example, when you register, we collect and store some or all of the following information that you provide: name, billing address, email address, telephone number, credit card number and expiration date. This information is used to provide the services that you have requested. Personal Information may also be collected in certain portions of the Website in which you specifically and knowingly provide such information. Some of this information also may be used to contact you about new site features, unless you have opted to not receive promotional communications in connection with the Website.

**Anonymous Information**  
Through your use of the Website, we may also gather certain information that does not identify you individually (“Anonymous Information”). Generally, this information is collected through “traffic data”. We may collect and store certain other information automatically whenever you interact with the Website. For example, we may collect your IP address, browser information and reference site domain name every time you visit the Website. We may also collect information regarding customer traffic patterns and site usage. This type of information can be used to analyze and improve the Website and to provide our customers with a fulfilling experience.

**Use of Cookies and Spyware**  
We never use or install spyware on your computer, nor do we use spyware to retrieve information from your computer.

We may use “cookies”, which are files stored on your computer’s hard drive by your browser, to identify account holders and to optimize their experience. Most browsers accept cookies automatically but allow you to disable them. We recommend that you leave cookies “turned on” so that we can offer you a better experience on the Website. You may occasionally get cookies from companies advertising on our behalf. We do not control these cookies, and these cookies are not subject to our cookie policy.

We also may collect and store information about you that we receive from other sources, to enable us to update and correct the information contained in our database.

**Is Information Collected From Children?**  
We do not collect any personal information from anyone who we know to be under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, you should use the Website only with the involvement of a parent or guardian and should not submit any personal information to us. Our Website is not intentionally targeted to children under the age of 13. Children under the age of 13 should not use our Website without obtaining prior parental consent.

**How We Use Your Information?**  
Except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy, we do not use or disclose information about your individual visits to our Website or your Personal Information collected online to any companies not affiliated with us. If we propose to permit any use of your Personal Information, you will be provided an opportunity to instruct us not to allow such contact.

**Customer Service and Feedback**  
We may use your Personal Information to provide customer service, track your compliance with the Website’s rules and regulations, or for editorial and feedback purposes (to the extent that is explained when you provide the information).

**Use of Anonymous Information**  
We use Anonymous Information to help us determine how people use parts of the Website and who our readers are so we can improve the Website and ensure that it is as appealing as we can make it for as many people as possible. We also use Anonymous Information to provide statistical “ratings” information in aggregated form to our partners and other third parties about how our users collectively use the Website. We may also use or share Anonymous Information (or other information, other than Personal Information) in any other manner that we deem appropriate or necessary.

**Third-party Agents**  
We occasionally have third party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates and partners that perform functions on our behalf, such as marketing, analytics, credit card processing, providing customer service, fraud protection, etc. These entities have access to the Personal Information needed to perform their functions and are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of that Personal Information. They are restricted from using, selling, distributing or altering this data in any way other than to provide the requested services to the Website.

**Transactional partners**  
We may share non-personal information with our partners and others from time to time. Examples of such non-personal information include the number of users who visited the Website during a specific time period. This information generally is shared in an aggregated form.

**Emergency Situations**  
We may also use or disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or the Website; (b) protect and defend the our rights or property, the Website or our users, and (c) act under emergency circumstances to protect the personal safety of us, our affiliates, agents, or the users of the Website or the public.

**What Steps Are Taken To Keep Personal Information Secure?**  
The importance of security for all Personal Information associated with you is of utmost concern to us. We exercise care in providing secure transmission of your information from your PC to our servers. Personal Information collected by the Website is stored in secure operating environments that are not available to the public. In many instances, such as in the case of credit card numbers, the Personal Information is encrypted before you conduct your transaction. Only those employees who need access to your Personal Information in order to do their jobs are allowed access. Any employee who violates our privacy and/or security policies is subject to disciplinary action, including possible termination and civil and/or criminal prosecution.

To protect the security of your information during transmission, we use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. Most browsers will give a visual indication of when your connection is secure. For example, Internet Explorer will show a padlock icon in the lower right of the browser window. If you register with the Website, you will be asked to register and provide an email address and password. In order to help protect your personal information further, you should be careful about providing your password to others. If you wish to cancel your password, or if you become aware of any loss, theft or unauthorized use of your password, please contact this Website’s Customer Service representative by email at shooley@iditarod.com.

While we try our best to safeguard your Personal Information once we receive it, no transmission of data over the Internet or any other public network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

**What Happens When I Link To or From Another Web Site?**  
The Website may contain links to other websites operated by affiliates of ITC or third parties. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy for the Website do not apply to information gathered through these other websites. These other sites may also send their own cookies to you, collect your data or solicit your personal information. Always be aware of where you end up. We are not responsible for the actions and privacy policies of third parties and other websites. We encourage you to be aware of when you leave the Website and to read the privacy policies of each and every website that you visit.

**Public Areas, Chat Rooms and Newsgroups**  
Please remember that any information you share in public areas, such as message boards or feedback sections, becomes public, and therefore this Privacy Policy does not apply to any information you choose to make public. Please be careful about what you disclose and do not post any Personal Information that you expect to keep private.

**Governing Law/Assignment**  
The Website is published in the United States. The laws of the State of Alaska shall govern in any and all disputes, including privacy or defamation issues or otherwise.

**GDPR**  
In accordance to GDPR, our European visitors should submit a support ticket to request more information about GDP and/or to download of the current data we have on file and/or request the deletion of your account and data.

**Changes to This Policy**  
As the Website continues to develop, we may add new services and features to the Website. In the event that these additions affect our Privacy Policy, this document will be updated appropriately. We will post those changes prominently so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone. We do, however, recommend that you read this Privacy Policy each time you use the Website in case you missed our notice of changes to the Privacy Policy.

**Opt-Out and Correction Procedures**  
You may opt-out of receiving future e-mail messages and other communications. There are several ways in which you can tell us whether or not you want to receive promotional communications from ITC. You will have an opportunity to change these selections by following the “unsubscribe” or “preference center” instructions contained in the promotional emails we send you. We also permit you to correct or update Personal Information that you have previously provided to us.

**Who do I talk to if I have more questions?**  
Questions regarding this statement should be directed to shooley@iditarod.com.
